

416-830-4792 chdshah@gmail.com

Toronto, ON

https://www.chitracodes.com/ https://github.com/chdtan/

SUMMARY

Hello! I'm Chitra! I am a former wall street Immigration Paralegal and a former tech recruiter. After 6+ years of working with software engineers & engineering teams, I decided to become a developer myself! Now, I no longer have to convince the US govn't of why software engineers are amazing....but I do have to convince you that I can become an amazing engineer and that more than anything, I have the will to learn! So here I am looking for a Developer position!

TECH SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

React

jQuery

Firebase

Git Version control

VS Code

Bloomberg Terminal

Excel (Pivot Tables & Pivot Reporting)

West Law & Nexis Lexis

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Best practices for modern web development Website accessibility requirements Presentation/Public Speaking Legal Writing & Research Immigration Law

PROJECTS

Tense Match A simple matching game of

verb tenses

https://bit.ly/2Imw0eY

DESCRIPTION & LINK

ι**0**οV

JavaScript(ES6), JQuery, HTML5, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design

TECHNOLOGIES USED

Desi

App to identify whether
Are they working in? current date is a working day or

current date is a working day of a national holiday in over 200 countries.

https://bit.ly/2IUfzpk

A vegan and vegetarian recipe generator.

https://bit.ly/2MSSuZA

Superfoods Navigator A nutrition facts generator.

https://bit.ly/2MWjdo2

Sass, Responsive Design, Accessible Design.

React, Dom Manipulation, CSS,

JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design, APIs, Accessible Design.

React, Firebase, API, CSS, Sass, Responsive Design, Accessible Design.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ANDIAMO, Toronto, CA 2018-2019

TITLE

Abbiocco

TECHNOLOGY TALENT ACQUISITION SPECIALIST

 Full life cycle recruitment of Software Engineers, Architects, and other tech talent for top tech/ financial institutions. e.g. Bloomberg, Amazon, HBO, Two Sigma, and more.

BLOOMBERG L.P. New York, USA | Toronto, CA 2017-2018

HR EXPERT-IMMIGRATION SPECIALIST

- Served as direct contact to 3000+ employees and various government agencies.
- Partnered with HR Business Partners, Engineering Managers, and Recruiting team on complex immigration matters and provide strategic immigration/ mobility analysis.

GEP WORLDWIDE New Jersey, USA 2015-2017

BUSINESS IMMIGRATION/GLOBAL MOBILITY SPECIALIST

- Single company wide point-of-contact for legal and immigration law related matters under direct supervision of General Counsel for global force of 2000+ employees.
- Provided guidance to senior management across all departments on all immigration related matters.

NPZ LAW GROUP, P.C. New Jersey, USA 2012-2015

IMMIGRATION PARALEGAL

- End to end preparation of petitions for filings before USCIS and direct consular filings at U.S. consulates abroad on behalf of tech, consulting, financial firms.
- SME for the law firm on DACA filings introduced in 2012 by President Obama.

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive (2019)

Accelerated Web Development Foundations/Advanced (2019)

American Bar Association Certified Paralegal Studies Program (2012)

Bachelor's Degree, Political Science (2010) HACKERYOU, COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY TORONTO, CANADA

HACKERYOU, COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY TORONTO, CANADA

FAIRLEIGH DICKINSON UNIVERSITY (USA)

RUTGERS, THE STATE UNIVERSITY OF NEW JERSEY (USA)